CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5831 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Kansas through New York, with Arizona, 1937-1942 (Reel 11)
  - CIO--Missouri., 1940; 25 (Reel 11)
    66 pp.: CIO organizers; organization of packing house workers; mass meetings; Labor's Non-Partisan League; income tax reform proposals; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors; J.R. Ferns; Allan S. Haywood; John Doherty; Neil Beam.
  - CIO--Missouri., 1941; 26 (Reel 11)
    17 pp.: CIO regional directors; Oil Workers International Union jurisdictional dispute with UMWA District 50; AFL-CIO competition; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; national defense mobilization efforts; Harvey C. Fremming; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Montana., 1938; 27 (Reel 11)
    8 pp.: CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; factionalism and internal politics; political activities; Walter Smethurst; Jerry J. O'Connell.
  - CIO--Montana., 1939; 28 (Reel 11)
    3 pp.: CIO regional directors; Joe Hunter.
  - CIO--Montana., 1940; 29 (Reel 11)
    5 pp.: 1940 state CIO convention; American Youth Congress; National Negro Congress. Sylvester Graham.
  - CIO--Montana., 1941; 30 (Reel 11)
    9 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; John Dwyer.
  - CIO--Nebraska., 1937; 31 (Reel 11)
    2 pp.: Union organization. See also CIO--Iowa and Nebraska file folder.
  - CIO--Nevada., 32 (Reel 11)
    Undated. 4 pp.: Anti-union violence and intimidation. See also CIO--New Mexico, Nevada, and Arizona file folder.
  - CIO--New England Council., 1937; 33 (Reel 11)
    6 pp.: CIO regional directors; ILGWU relations with UERMWA; factionalism and internal politics; organizing drives; Michael F. Widman; Walter Smethurst; Powers Hapgood; Joseph A. Salerno.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1937; 34 (Reel 11)
    8 pp.: Strikes; social events; legislative programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO organizers; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Kathryn Lewis; Earl E. Houck.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1938; 35 (Reel 11)
    9 pp.: CIO regional directors; proposed pen and pencil workers organizing committee; Walter Smethurst; W.J. Carney.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1939; 36 (Reel 11)
    25 pp.: CIO regional directors; labor management cooperation; CIO retention of outside legal counsel in US Supreme Court case involving Mayor Frank Hague of Jersey City, NJ; ACLU cooperation with CIO; strikes; public relations activities; UMWA District 50; CIO organizers; anti-labor decisions of NLRB; AFL-CIO competition; AFL-CIO cooperation; W.J. Carney; Lee Pressman; John Brophy; Morris Ernst; James Nelson; Leonard H. Goldsmith.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1940; 37 (Reel 11)
    123 pp.: CIO organizers; factionalism and internal politics; 1940 state CIO convention; criticism and support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; ACWA failure to pay per capita and suspension from state CIO; minutes of state CIO executive council meetings; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Allan S. Haywood; Leonard H. Goldsmith; W.J. Carney; Kathryn Lewis; Carl Holderman; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1941; 38 (Reel 11)
    20 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; Labor's Non-Partisan League; criticism of Labor's Non-Partisan League chairmanship of John L. Lewis; support of UMWA in captive mines dispute; Leonard H. Goldsmith; Irving Abramson.
  - CIO--New Jersey., 1942; 39 (Reel 11)
    4 pp.: Criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; war mobilization efforts.
  - CIO--New Mexico, Nevada and Arizona., 1937; 40 (Reel 11)
    2 pp.: 1937 joint state CIO convention.
  - CIO--New York., 1937; 41 (Reel 11)
    41 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; strikes; NLRB elections; labor racketeering; Alabama anti-union violence and intimidation; Allan S. Haywood; Pete Mosele; Sherman H. Dalrymple.
- New York through Oklahoma, 1938-1942 (Reel 12)
  - CIO--New York., 1938; 1 (Reel 12)
    90 pp.: Legislative programs; union organization; contract negotiations; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; reorganization of local industrial unions; Transport Workers Union; AFL-CIO competition; workmen's compensation matters; political activities; Allan S. Haywood; Sidney Hillman; Ora E. Gasaway; A.D. Lewis; Pete Mosele; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; Hugh Thompson; Rinaldo Cappellini; Thomas Kennedy; John Brophy; W.P. Hapgood.
  - CIO--New York., 1939; 2 (Reel 12)
    42 pp.: Legislative programs; press relations; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO regional directors; NLRB hearings; AFL-CIO competition in Cleveland, Ohio; CIO organizers; support for UMWA contract negotiations; strikes; 1939 state CIO convention; Adolph Germer; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway; Pete Mosele; John P. Frey; Rinaldo Cappellini; James B. Carey; John Brophy; Fiorello H. La Guardia.
  - CIO--New York., 1940; 3 (Reel 12)
    133 pp.: Political activities; factionalism and internal politics; national defense mobilization efforts; legislative programs; disputed 1940 state CIO convention; NLRB decisions of William E. Leiserson favoring crafts unions; AFL-CIO competition; CIO organizers and regional directors; press relations; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; allegations of Communist influence; support for CIO and UMWA presidencies of John L. Lewis; Saul Mills; Kathryn Lewis; Joseph Curran; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Michael Quill; Abram Flaxer; Frederick Myer; John F. Ryan; Arthur Osman; Samuel Wolchok; Allan S. Haywood; Vito Marcantonio; Sidney Hillman; Gustave A. Strebel; Lee Pressman; Hugh Thompson; Adolph Germer; William Green; Ralph Tillotson; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--New York., 1941; 4 (Reel 12)
    55 pp.: Council meeting minutes; political activities; strikes; union organization; UMWA District 50; jurisdictional disputes involving the United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO organizers; national defense mobilization efforts; legislative programs; NMU; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Joseph Curran; Saul Mills; A.D. Lewis; James B. Carey; Len De Caux.
  - CIO--New York., 1942; 5 (Reel 12)
    8 pp.: Legislative programs; war mobilization efforts; contract negotiations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis, UMWA District 50 organization of Dairy Farmers Union, and UMWA expulsion of Philip Murray; council meeting minutes; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Gustave A. Strebel; Austin Hogan; Saul Mills.
  - CIO--North Carolina., 1938; 6 (Reel 12)
    4 pp.: CIO organization of tobacco workers; AFL-CIO competition; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; E.L. Sandefur.
  - CIO--Ohio., 1937; 7 (Reel 12)
    53 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; factionalism and internal politics; organization of packing house workers in Iowa; NLRB case involving cooperation by Massillon, Ohio, public officials; mass meetings; Ora E. Gasaway; Thomas Davis; Walter Smethurst; Kathryn Lewis; Lee Hall; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Don Harris; John Owens; A.D> Lewis; Malcolm Ross; August Scholle; Clinton S. Golden.
  - CIO--Ohio., 1938; 8 (Reel 12)
    157 pp.: Political activities; Labor's Non-Partisan League; support for New Deal legislative programs; use of National Guard as strikebreakers in Middleton, Ohio; NLRB decisions; AFL-CIO competition; SWOC; CIO organizers and regional directors; legislative programs; support for WPA budget appropriations; proceedings of 1938 state CIO convention; Len De Caux; Ted F. Silvey; John Owens; Martin L. Davey; Philip Murray; B.J. Damich; Van A. Bittner; Lee Hall; A.F. Whitney; Adolph Pacifico; Kathryn Lewis; Adolph Germer; John Brophy; David J. McDonald; Eli L. Oliver; James B. Carey; George F. Addes; Frank Barnhart; Richard Frankensteen; Irwin L. DeShetler.
  - CIO--Ohio., 1939; 9 (Reel 12)
    41 pp.: Radio programs; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; SWOC; press relations; contract negotiations; legislatives programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; political activities; Ted F. Silvey; Paul W. Fuller; Ora E. Gasaway; Lee Pressman; A.D. Lewis; John Brophy; Michael Gallagher; John Owens; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Ohio., 1940; 10 (Reel 12)
    72 pp.: Legislative programs; political activities; Labor's Non-Partisan League; UMWA district presidents; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA District 50; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Adolph Pacifico; Ted F. Silvey; Kathryn Lewis; Paul W. Fuller; Ora E. Gasaway; Allan S. Haywood; John Brophy; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--Ohio., 1941; 11 (Reel 12)
    71 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; organizing drives; jurisdictional disputes between Aluminum Workers of America, UAW, and National Association of Die Casting Workers; 1940 constitution of state CIO; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Ted F. Silvey; John Owens; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis; Percy Tetlow; Philip Murray; Edward T. Cheyfitz; N.A. Zonarich; Robert J. Davidson; Franklin D. Roosevelt
  - CIO--Ohio., 1942; 12 (Reel 12)
    9 pp.: Criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for CIO presidency of Philip Murray; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; war mobilization efforts; Ted F. Silvey
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1937; 13 (Reel 12)
    12 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; factionalism and internal politics; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO competition; John Wilkinson; David Fowler.
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1938; 14 (Reel 12)
    41 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; AFL-CIO competition; IUMMSW contract negotiations; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA support for CIO; "Arkansas-Oklahoma Industrial Union Council Bulletin"; Labor's Non-Partisan League; financial matters; radio broadcasts; David Fowler; J.D. Kimberling; John Brophy.
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1939; 15 (Reel 12)
    52 pp.: UMWA support for CIO; financial matters; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; proposed amendment of the Wagner Act; Workers Alliance of America; allegation of Communist influence; political activities; proceedings of the 1939 state CIO convention; David Fowler; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1940; 16 (Reel 12)
    10 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO competition; proposed organization of train porters; Oil Workers International Union; CIO organizers; factionalism and internal politics; David Fowler; Allan S. Haywood.
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1941; 17 (Reel 12)
    5 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA District 50; union organization; contract negotiations; David Fowler.
  - CIO--Oklahoma., 1942; 18 (Reel 12)
    3 pp.: Support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis.
- Oregon through Pennsylvania, 1937-1942 (Reel 13)
  - CIO--Oregon., 1937; 1 (Reel 13)
    5 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; AFL boycott of CIO-produced lumber; Kathryn Lewis; E.B. O'Grady.
  - CIO--Oregon., 1938; 2 (Reel 13)
    5 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; Kathryn Lewis; James Fantz.
  - CIO--Oregon., 3 (Reel 13)
    Undated. 2 pp.: CIO regional directors; state CIO convention; Richard Francis; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Oregon., 1940; 4 (Reel 13)
    113 pp.: CIO regional directors; factionalism and internal politics among ladies auxiliaries of the IWA; National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; 1940 CIO convention; CIO factionalism and internal politics; IWA factionalism and internal politics; Inland Boatman's Union; 1940 Washington state CIO convention@United Furniture Workers of America; AFL-CIO competition; NLRB elections; Communist influence and anti- Communist activities in CIO; criticism of ILWU presidency and West Coast CIO directorship of Harry Bridges; radio broadcasts; national defense mobilization efforts; Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense; jurisdictional disputes between ILWU and Textile Workers Union of America; anti-war sentiments; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; IWA organizing campaigns; IWA organizers; proposed amendments to the Wagner Act; political activities; US Department of Labor; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie@United Federal Workers of America; 1940 state CIO convention; support for UMWA and CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis; William Dalrymple; Kathryn Lewis; Allan S. Haywood; Morris Muster; Adolph Germer; John M. Brost; Sidney Hillman; Lee Pressman; Ralph W. Peoples; Thomas Kennedy.
  - CIO--Oregon., 1941; 5 (Reel 13)
    70 pp.: CIO regional directors; legislative programs; political activities; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Office of Production Management; National Defense Mediation Board; national defense mobilization efforts; anti-labor bias; competition between United Construction Workers Organizing Committee and IBT; CIO organizers; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; union organization in Alabama; anti-strike policies of the Civil Service System; ILWU and CIO factionalism and internal politics; SWOC membership in California; radio broadcasts; UMWA organizers and personnel matters; 1941 state CIO convention; tribute to CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; William Dalrymple; Ralph W. Peoples; Philip Murray; John M. Brost; Franklin D. Roosevelt; A.D. Lewis; Sidney Hillman; John B. Whitson; James B. Carey; Kathryn Lewis; Louis Goldblatt.
  - CIO--Oregon., 1942; 6 (Reel 13)
    40 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; plans for 1942 Washington state CIO convention; radio broadcasts; IWA and Aluminum Workers of America organization matters; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in CIO; UMWA district presidents; UMWA District 50 organizers; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1942 state CIO convention; William Dalrymple; Allan S. Haywood; William Mitch; Ralph W. Peoples.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Committee for Industrial Organization., 1937; 7 (Reel 13)
    69 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; labor racketeering; CIO organizers and regional directors; financial matters; regional coordination between CIO affiliates; SWOC; TWOC; NLRB elections; cooperation between IBT and Bakery Workers International Union; AFL-CIO competition; mass meetings; John Brophy; Joseph D. Cannon; Ralph Tillotson; B.J. Damich; John Edelman; Bernard Levinson; William Leader; A.D. Lewis.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh., 1937; 8 (Reel 13)
    2 pp.: Youngstown, Ohio, area strikes; requests for intercession with Home Owners Loan Corporation; Lee Pressman; A.D. Lewis.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania., 1938; 9 (Reel 13)
    117 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; political activities; proceedings of the 1938 state CIO convention; UMWA organizers; NLRB decisions; SWOC; ACWA; TWOC; David J. McDonald; John Edelman; Kathryn Lewis; Ralph Tillotson; John A. Phillips; Thomas Kennedy; A.D. Lewis; James B. Carey; John Brophy; Philip Murray; Leo Krzycki; Michael Quill; Emil Rieve.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania., 1939; 10 (Reel 13)
    120 pp.: Minutes of meetings; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO cooperation; union organization; Textile Workers Union of America organizers; AFL-CIO competition; legislative programs; state Workmen's Compensation Act; brief amicus curiae filed by CIO and Textile Workers Union of America in William Leader and American Federation of Full Fashioned Hosiery Workers, Philadelphia, Branch No. 1, Local 706 v. Apex Hosiery Corporation (US Circuit Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit); Sherman Antitrust Act; CIO policy regarding expense accounts for organizers; mass meetings; 1939 state CIO convention; SWOC organizers; support for UMWA in contract negotiations; resolutions regarding 1940 US presidential elections and anti-war sentiments; Allan S. Haywood; Michael J. Kosik; John Kmetz; John Brophy; Walter Smethurst; Garfield Lewis; John A. Phillips; Lee Pressman; Joseph Kovner; Anthony Wayne Smith; Philip Murray; J. Raymond Bell; Joseph D. Cannon; A.D. Lewis; David J. McDonald.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania., 1940; 11 (Reel 13)
    119 pp.: Legislative programs; American Labor Party; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support and criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA local union organization; national defense mobilization and neutrality efforts; UMWA-CIO cooperation@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; plans for John L. Lewis's appearance before the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP); 1940 state CIO convention; Transport Workers Union contract negotiations; political activities; AFL-CIO local cooperation; organizing campaigns; voter registration efforts; Labor's Non-Partisan League; John A. Philips; Anthony J. Federoff; P.T. Fagan; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; Michael J. Kosik; Joseph D. Cannon; Philip Murray; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood; William Leader; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania., 1941; 12 (Reel 13)
    139 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; proposed unionization of mine foremen; unemployment compensation legislation; national defense mobilization and anti-war sentiments; proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; legislative programs; UMWA district presidents; John A. Philips; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Arthur H. James; J. Raymond Bell; Ora E. Gasaway; O.F. Nigro; George Craig; Philip Murray; John Kmetz; Leo Krzycki; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood; David J. McDonald.
  - CIO--Pennsylvania., 1942; 13 (Reel 13)
    108 pp.: CIO factionalism and internal politics; war mobilization efforts; criticism of UMWA expulsion of Philip Murray; violence and intimidation; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; state unemployment compensation legislation; proceedings of the 1942 state CIO convention; legislative programs; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO relations; John A. Philips; Anthony J. Federoff; Philip Murray; Allan S. Haywood; Van A. Bittner; John Brophy; James B. Carey; David J. McDonald; James Mark; John O'Leary; Jake Yablonsky; John Kmetz.
- Rhode Island through West Virginia, 1937-1942 (Reel 14)
  - CIO--Rhode Island., 1937; 1 (Reel 14)
    3 pp.: CIO organizers; Joseph Mayo.
  - CIO--Rhode Island., 1938; 2 (Reel 14)
    10 pp.: CIO organizers; CIO lawsuit against local textile unions' unauthorized use of CIO initials; TWOC; Joseph Mayo; A.D. Lewis; Lee Pressman.
  - CIO--Rhode Island., 1939; 3 (Reel 14)
    9 pp.: CIO regional directors and organizers; SWOC; TWOC; UMWA District 50; Joseph Mayo; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Anne Marsoli.
  - CIO--Rhode Island., 1940; 4 (Reel 14)
    5 pp.: CIO regional directors and organizers; 1940 state CIO convention; Joseph Mayo; Ora E. Gasaway; Anne Marsoli.
  - CIO--Rhode Island., 1941; 5 (Reel 14)
    3 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; CIO organizers and regional directors; Joseph Mayo; Anne Marsoli.
  - CIO--South Dakota., 1941; 6 (Reel 14)
    4 pp.: Local union criticism of CIO regional directors; PWOC cooperation with IBT; J. Raymond Bell.
  - CIO--Tennessee., 1937; 7 (Reel 14)
    4 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; press relations; Kathryn Lewis; T.J. Smith.
  - CIO--Tennessee., 1938; 8 (Reel 14)
    6 pp.:Alliance of America; southern regional conference; T.J. Smith; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Tennessee., 1940; 9 (Reel 14)
    22 pp.: UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO cooperation; political activities; proceedings of the 1940 state CIO convention; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; William Turnblazer; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Tennessee., 1941; 10 (Reel 14)
    41 pp.: Proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Harry Bridges Defense Committee; national defense mobilization efforts; financial matters; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Henry Pirtle v. H.B. Brown, Christian Kopp, and W.F. Warren (petition for writ of certiorari filed before the US Supreme Court as a challenge to enforcement of southern poll taxes by the Judges of Election for the Fifth Civil District of Grundy County, Tennessee); Paul R. Christopher; Kathryn Lewis; Lee Pressman; Crampton Harris
  - CIO--Texas., 1939; 11 (Reel 14)
    4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; financial matters; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood.
  - CIO--Texas., 1940; 12 (Reel 14)
    14 pp.: 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; 1940 Oil Workers International Union convention; CIO organizers and regional directors; political activities. Maurice J. Dineen; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Utah., 1947; 13 (Reel 14)
    13 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; AFL expulsion of CIO affiliates; CIO regional directors; UMWA contract negotiations; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; James Morgan; Ora E. Gasaway; Walter Smethurst.
  - CIO--Utah., 1939; 14 (Reel 14)
    18 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1939 Washington state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; plans for 1939 CIO convention; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; IUMMSW-AFL cooperation in Colorado, Montana, and Utah; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA organizers and district presidents; James Morgan; A.M. Peterson; Walter Smethurst.
  - CIO--Utah., 1940; 15 (Reel 14)
    23 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; SWOC organization of ethnic workers in Colorado; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; IUMMSW contract negotiations; political activities; UMWA District 50; 1940 state CIO convention; legislative programs; James Morgan; Walter N. Polakov; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--Utah., 1941; 16 (Reel 14)
    14 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; NLRB elections; CIO-UMWA cooperation; 1941 state CIO convention; SWOC organization of ethnic workers in Colorado; Inland Empire CIO Organizing Committee; James Morgan.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1937; 17 (Reel 14)
    15 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; organization of tobacco workers; contract negotiations; NLRB hearings; Virginia Better Business Bureau's anti-CIO activities; union organization; growth in membership of CIO; Ray Thomason; Ora E. Gasaway; John Suttle; Mont Crum.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1938; 18 (Reel 14)
    3 pp.: Plans for mass meeting in WV.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1939; 19 (Reel 14)
    36 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; plans for 1939 CIO convention; organizing campaigns; financial matters; UMWA organizers and district presidents; growth in membership of CIO; UMWA contract negotiations; Ben Williams; Ora E. Gasaway; Ray Thomason; Kathryn Lewis; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Walter Smethurst; A.D. Lewis; James Mark, Jr.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1940; 20 (Reel 14)